LALIT CHOUDHARY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

✓ <u>Lalitchoudhary4816@gmail.com</u>

+917738994816

in www.linkedin.com/in/lalit-choudhary-142643172

EDUCATION

2020 - 2022 MUMBAI UNIVERSITY

- Master In Computer Science
- GPA: 8.4/10

PROFILE SUMMARY

With 3+ years of experience in WordPress development, I specialize in plugin development, theme customization, and performance optimization. I have developed many functional features for various websites, helping improve company workflows and cutting costs by 80% on third-party expenses or pro plugin charges. Along with WordPress, I have knowledge of various front-end technologies and libraries and can develop any type of WordPress page or design with full responsiveness and functionality.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- PHP
- Bootstrap
- · Plugin development
- WP Theme Customization
- Browser Developer
- Figma
- SEO
- WooCommerce
- cPanel & Web Hosting
- Git & GitHub
- WordPress Security
- Page Builders
- WP Hooks
- Database Management
- API Integration

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sunflower Lab - WFH

FEB 2023 — PRESENT

Software Developer

- Engineered custom plugins to replace expensive third-party solutions, lowering operational expenses by 80% and optimizing project workflows.
- Developed advanced features, including a fully automated NDA agreement system with digital signature integration and a custombuilt ROI calculator to enhance user experience and streamline business operations.
- Optimized website performance, reducing load times by 50% and ensuring compliance with web vitals for both desktop and mobile.

LearnKartS — Bengaluru, Karnataka

JUN 2022 — JAN 2023

WordPress Developer

- Collaborated with design team to create 100% responsive and user-friendly websites.
- Implemented advanced WordPress functionality and hooks to enhance website customization and accelerate development efficiency by 30%.
- Configured Custom Post Type UI to organize content effectively by creating and managing custom post types and taxonomies.

BLUeSINGA — Remote

OCT 2021 — MAY 2022

WordPress Developer

- Orchestrated the in-house marketing team's website operations, enhancing 50+ pages and posts to drive higher user engagement.
- Developed and optimized fully responsive pages and posts, ensuring seamless accessibility and a 100% mobile-friendly experience across all devices.

LANGUAGES

• English: Intermediate

• Hindi: Fluent

Marathi: Fluent

Marwadi: Fluent

• Gujrati: Intermediate

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATES

Innovative Contribution Award — Sunflower Lab

 Recognized for developing cost-effective and innovative WordPress solutions, including custom plugin development that reduced third-party expenses by 70-80%, optimized website performance, and enhanced user experience.

Python development Certificates - MU

Android development Certificates - MU

INTERNSHIP

• IT Security & Development — BLUeSINGA

Cyber Security Analyst — Pristine Infosolutions

NOV 2020 - APR 2021

OCT 2019 - MAR 2020

PORTFOLIO/PROJECTS

- https://lalit-choudhary-wp.github.io/wordpress-portfolio/
- https://www.thesunflowerlab.com/
- https://www.heeythere.com/
- https://www.bluesinga.com/
- https://www.learnkarts.com/
- https://zinniax.com/
- +More